https://www.teresaflavin.com/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Privacy PolicyTeresa2019-06-19T12:12:40+00:00Privacy PolicyI am committed to safeguarding the privacy of my website visitors and service users. For this reason, I collect and use personal data only as it may be needed to deliver my products, services and website to you.My Privacy Policy describes how and what data I collect, and how and why I use your personal data. This policy applies where I am acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of my website visitors and service users; in other words, where I determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data. It also describes options I provide for you to access, update or otherwise take control of your personal data that I collect.By using my website and agreeing to this policy, you consent to my use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy.If at any time you have questions about my Privacy Policy, please contact me.What Information do I collect? I collect email addresses of people who have emailed me and to whom I have replied. These are automatically saved in my Gmail account.I collect email addresses and names of people who have signed up to my mailing list via the opt-in link on my website and held on my behalf by iContact.com.I have access to databases of followers on Twitter, Facebook and Instagram. I am the data controller but not the data processor of these databases – I use strong passwords and two factor authentication on these sites.I have a YouTube account where viewers may comment. I generally reply, but I hold no data about them. YouTube hold this data. I use strong passwords and two factor authorisation on my YouTube channel.How I use your dataIf you provide identifying information in an email, such as your name and address, your information is used only to communicate with you and to deal with your request. If you provide personal information for information requests, subscribing to my newsletter and/or any other reason, only my authorised agents and I will process your request as follows:I may access usage data about your use of my website. The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. I do not process information about individual users. The source of the usage data is the Google Analytics tracking system. I view this usage data to analyse the use of my website. The legal basis for accessing usage data is my legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving my website and services.I may collect your personal data provided in the course of your use of my services. The service data may include your name, address, telephone number and email address. The source of the service data is you. I may collect the service data for the purposes of operating my website, providing my services, ensuring the security of my website and services, maintaining back-ups of my databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is consent; the proper administration of my website and business; the performance of a contract between us and/or taking steps to enter into such a contract at your request.I may collect information contained in any enquiry you submit to me regarding goods and/or services. This enquiry data may be collected for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent.I collect information that you provide to me, via the opt-in link on my website, for the purpose of subscribing you to my monthly newsletters. The notification data is collected and securely stored for the purposes of sending you the relevant newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is consent.I may collect information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to me. The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. My website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using my website contact forms. The correspondence data may be collected for the purposes of communicating with you and for my record-keeping. The legal basis for this is the proper administration of my website and business and communications with users.I may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is my legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of my legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.I may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is my legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of my business against risks.In addition to the specific purposes for which I may process your personal data set out in this section, I may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which I am subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.To the extent I am legally permitted to do so, I will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that I am required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of legal process. Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to me, unless I prompt you to do so.Providing your personal data to othersI will not disclose your personal data to others except in the these instances:I may disclose your personal data to my insurers and/or professional advisers insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this section, I may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which I am subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. I may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.International transfers of your personal dataMy business and the hosting facilities for my website are situated with Heart Internet in the United Kingdom. If you utilise my services from a country other than the country where Heart’s servers are located, your communications with me may result in transferring your personal data across international borders.When you opt in to subscribe to my newsletter, your personal data (name and email address) is transferred by me and processed outside of the EEA by iContact.In these cases, your personal data is handled according to this Privacy Policy. For more information on how Heart Internet and iContact process and store data, please read their Privacy Policies.How I retain and delete your personal dataPersonal data that I collect for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.In some cases it is not possible for me to specify in advance the periods for which I will retain your personal data. The period of retention of my newsletter subscribers will be determined based on the length of time they continue to opt in or the newsletter no longer being sent out to subscribers.Consent is not indefinite. I will remind subscribers that they can unsubscribe or ask for their data to be removed.Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, I may retain your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which I am subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.Updating informationPlease let me know if the personal information that I hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.How I secure and store your dataI take appropriate technical and organisational precautions to secure your personal data and to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal data.I store all your personal data on secure servers, personal computers and mobile devices, and in secure manual record-keeping systems if used.I have strongly password-protected and firewalled my computer, devices and website as well as iContact, Google, Dropbox, Twitter, Facebook and Instagram accounts with two step authentication. If any of those organisations were compromised, I will immediately take steps to follow their advice.You acknowledge that the transmission of unencrypted (or inadequately encrypted) data over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.Age Restrictions and Children’s PrivacyIt is important to me that children enjoy my site in a responsible way and with the knowledge and approval of their parents or guardians. Therefore, if you are under 16, please read this policy with your parents or guardians and ask questions about things you do not understand.I am committed to protecting your online privacy when you visit my website. I do not collect and keep any personal information from you unless you volunteer it and you are 16 or older.If you are under 16 and send a question or request to me through my website, I will only keep your email address for long enough to respond to you. I will delete your information from my system after I have answered your question.If you are under 16 and would like to receive my newsletter, please ask your parents or guardians to sign up to my newsletter with their email address. If you or your parents and guardians no longer wish to receive information from me, the subscriber can unsubscribe by using the Unsubscribe link at the end of the newsletters.Neither your screen name nor your parent or guardian’s email address will be posted, sold, rented or traded to third parties.Young people may also comment on my YouTube videos, Instagram or Twitter posts. I don’t know their ages unless they tell me. If they mention their ages I will immediately delete their comment.I encourage parents to supervise their children’s online activities by adopting parental control tools available from online services and software companies. These tools can prevent children from disclosing their personal information online without their parents’ or guardians’ permission.If you have any further questions, please contact me at:East Street Arts, Patrick Studios, St Mary’s Lane, Leeds LS9 7EH, United KingdomLinks to third-party websitesMy website may provide links to other sites that I do not control. I am not responsible for the security or use of information by companies or organisations that may be linked to my website. You are advised to review the privacy policy of websites you access through links from my site before you provide personal or confidential information.Your rightsIn this section, I have summarised your rights under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in my summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.Your principal rights under data protection law are: the right to access, to rectification, to erasure, to processing, to restrict, to object to processing, to data portability, to complain to a supervisory authority, to withdraw consent.You have the right to confirm whether or not I process your personal data and, where I do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, I will supply a copy of your personal data to you. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee.You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; I no longer need the personal data for the purposes of my processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, I may continue to store your personal data. However, I will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.You have the right to object to my processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in me; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by me or by a third party. If you make such an objection, I will cease to process the personal information unless I can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.You have the right to object to my collection of your personal data for direct marketing purposes. If you make such an objection, I will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.To the extent that the legal basis for my processing of your personal data is:(a)        consent; or(b)       that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from me in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.If you consider that my collection of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.To the extent that the legal basis for my processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to me. I aim to respond within 24 hours of receipt.About cookiesA cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that is stored about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.Cookies that I and my service providers useCategory: Necessary (2)Necessary cookies help make a website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot function properly without these cookies.COOKIE NAMEPROVIDERTYPEEXPIRYCookieConsentteresaflavin.comHTTP1 yearFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Stores the user’s cookie consent state for the current domainInitiator: Script tag Source: notinstalledData is sent to: Ireland (adequate) csrftokeninstagram.comHTTP1 yearFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/Cookie purpose description: Helps prevent Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF) attacks.Initiator: Script tag Source: https://www.teresaflavin.com/Data is sent to: United States (adequate) Category: Statistics (6) Statistic cookies help website owners to understand how visitors interact with websites by collecting and reporting information anonymously.COOKIE NAMEPROVIDERTYPEEXPIRY@@History/@@scroll|#youtube.comHTMLSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/videos/Cookie purpose description: UnclassifiedInitiator: Webserver Source: youtube.comData is sent to: Netherlands (adequate) _gateresaflavin.comHTTP2 yearsFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.Initiator: Page source line number 129-135 Source: Inline scriptData is sent to: Germany (adequate) _gatteresaflavin.comHTTPSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rateInitiator: Page source line number 129-135 Source: Inline scriptData is sent to: Germany (adequate) _gidteresaflavin.comHTTPSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.Initiator: Page source line number 129-135 Source: Inline scriptData is sent to: Germany (adequate) collectgoogle-analytics.comPixelSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.Initiator: Inline script, page source line number 129-135 Source: https://www.google-analytics.com/r/collectData is sent to: Netherlands (adequate) vuidvimeo.comHTTP2 yearsFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/videos/Cookie purpose description: Collects data on the user’s visits to the website, such as which pages have been read.Initiator: Script tag Source: https://www.teresaflavin.com/videos/Data is sent to: United States (adequate) Category: Marketing (7) Marketing cookies are used to track visitors across websites. The intention is to display ads that are relevant and engaging for the individual user and thereby more valuable for publishers and third party advertisers.COOKIE NAMEPROVIDERTYPEEXPIRYGPSyoutube.comHTTPSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Registers a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.Initiator: Inline script, page source line number 129-135 Source: Data is sent to: Netherlands (adequate) mcdinstagram.comHTTPSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/Cookie purpose description: UnclassifiedInitiator: Script tag Source: https://www.teresaflavin.com/Data is sent to: United States (adequate) PREFyoutube.comHTTP8 monthsFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites.Initiator: Inline script, page source line number 129-135 Source: Data is sent to: Netherlands (adequate) rurinstagram.comHTTPSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/Cookie purpose description: UnclassifiedInitiator: Script tag Source: https://www.teresaflavin.com/Data is sent to: United States (adequate) urlgeninstagram.comHTTPSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/Cookie purpose description: UnclassifiedInitiator: Script tag Source: https://www.teresaflavin.com/Data is sent to: United States (adequate) VISITOR_INFO1_LIVEyoutube.comHTTP179 daysFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Tries to estimate the users’ bandwidth on pages with integrated YouTube videos.Initiator: Inline script, page source line number 129-135 Source: Data is sent to: Netherlands (adequate) YSCyoutube.comHTTPSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.Initiator: Inline script, page source line number 129-135 Source: Data is sent to: Netherlands (adequate) Category: Unclassified (1) Unclassified cookies are cookies that we are in the process of classifying, together with the providers of individual cookies.COOKIE NAMEPROVIDERTYPEEXPIRYe/irassoc-amazon.co.ukPixelSessionFirst found URL: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Cookie purpose description: UnclassifiedInitiator: Script tag Source: https://www.teresaflavin.com/category/books-and-publishing/page/2/Data is sent to: Ireland (adequate) Cookies used by my service providersMy service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit my website.I use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to my website is used to create reports about the use of my website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.Managing cookiesMost browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:(a)        https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);(b)       https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);(c)        http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);(d)       https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);(e)       https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and(f)        https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on my website.Data Protection by Design and Data Protection Impact AssessmentsI have familiarised myself with the ICO’s (Information Commissioners Office UK) code of practice on Privacy Impact Assessments as well as the latest guidance from the Article 29 Working Party, and believe that I am using best practice.My details:This website is owned and operated by Teresa Flavin.My principal place of business is at Patrick Studios, East Street Arts, St Mary’s Lane, Leeds LS9 7EH, United Kingdom.You can contact me:by post, to the postal address given aboveusing my website contact form.
This website uses cookies. By continuing to use this website you are giving consent to these cookies being used.ACCEPTREAD PRIVACY POLICY
Go to Top
